<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R@ndom Musings</title>
    <link>https://MeChowy.github.io/tags/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R@ndom Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 17:00:56 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://MeChowy.github.io/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hard Thing About Hard Things</title>
      <link>https://mechowy.github.io/book/hard-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 17:00:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mechowy.github.io/book/hard-things/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;qoutes&#34;&gt;Qoutes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In life, everybody faces choices between doing what’s popular, easy, and wrong versus doing what’s lonely, difficult, and right&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no such thing as a great executive. There is only a great executive for a specific company at a specific point in time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s important to supplement a great product vision with a strong discipline around the metrics, but if you substitute metrics for product vision, you will not get what you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We take care of the people, the products, and the profits—in that order.”&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a simple saying, but it’s deep. “Taking care of the people” is the most difficult of the three by far and if you don’t do it, the other two won’t matter. Taking care of the people means that your company is a good place to work.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In life, everybody faces choices between doing what’s popular, easy, and wrong versus doing what’s lonely, difficult, and right. These decisions intensify when you run a company, because the consequences get magnified a thousandfold. As in life, the excuses for CEOs making the wrong choice are always plentiful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;there is an acronym for it, WFIO, which stands for “We’re Fucked, It’s Over” (it’s pronounced “whiff-ee-yo”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think of the organizational design as the communications architecture for your company. If you want people to communicate, the best way to accomplish that is to make them report to the same manager. By contrast, the further away people are in the organizational chart, the less they will communicate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve seen executives improve their performance and skill sets, I’ve never seen one lose the support of the organization and then regain it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are going to eat shit, don&amp;rsquo;t nibble.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were lots of companies in the ’90s that had launch parties but no landing parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;when you run an engineering organization is that a good quality assurance organization cannot build a high-quality product, but it can tell you when the development team builds a low quality product. Similarly, a high quality human resources organization cannot make you a well-managed company with a great culture, but it can tell you when you and your managers are not getting the job done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing motivates a great employee more than a mission that’s so important that it supersedes everyone’s personal ambition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you investigate companies that have failed, you will find that many employees knew about the fatal issues long before those issues killed the company. If the employees knew about the deadly problems, why didn’t they say something? Too often the answer is that the company culture discouraged the spread of bad news, so the knowledge lay dormant until it was too late to act. A healthy company culture encourages people to share bad news. A company that discusses its problems freely and openly can quickly solve them. A company that covers up its problems frustrates everyone involved. The resulting action item for CEOs: Build a culture that rewards—not punishes—people for getting problems into the open where they can be solved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is not checkers; this is motherfuckin’ chess.&lt;/strong&gt; Technology businesses tend to be extremely complex. The underlying technology moves, the competition moves, the market moves, the people move. As a result, like playing three-dimensional chess on Star Trek, there is always a move. You think you have no moves? How about taking your company public with \$2 million in trailing revenue and 340 employees, with a plan to do $75 million in revenue the next year? I made that move. I made it in 2001, widely regarded as the worst time ever for a technology company to go public. I made it with six weeks of cash left. &lt;strong&gt;There is always a move.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;when done properly, feedback is a dialogue, not a monologue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Son, do you know what’s cheap?” Since I had absolutely no idea what he was talking about, I replied, “No, what?” “Flowers. Flowers are really cheap. But do you know what’s expensive?” he asked. Again, I replied, “No, what?” He said,“Divorce.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you expect your employees to act like adults, they generally do. If you treat them like children, then get ready for your company to turn into one big Barney episode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sometimes an organization doesn’t need a solution; it just needs clarity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good product managers crisply define the target, the “what” (as opposed to the “how”), and manage the delivery of the “what.” Bad product managers feel best about themselves when they figure out “how.” Good product managers communicate crisply to engineering in writing as well as verbally. Good product managers don’t give direction informally. Good product managers gather information informally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The key to a good one-on-one meeting is the understanding that it is the employee’s meeting rather than the manager’s meeting. This is the free-form meeting for all the pressing issues, brilliant ideas, and chronic frustrations that do not fit neatly into status reports, email, and other less personal and intimate mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good practice is to have the employee send you the agenda in advance. This will give her a chance to cancel the meeting if nothing is pressing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bunch of high-IQ people with the wrong kind of ambition won’t work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you run a company, you will experience overwhelming psychological pressure to be overly positive. &lt;strong&gt;Stand up to the pressure, face your fear, and tell it like it is.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Struggle is when you wonder why you started the company in the first place. The Struggle is when people ask you why you don’t quit and you don’t know the answer. The Struggle is when your employees think you are lying and you think they may be right. The Struggle is when food loses its taste. The Struggle is when you don’t believe you should be CEO of your company. The Struggle is when you know that you are in over your head and you know that you cannot be replaced. The Struggle is when everybody thinks you are an idiot, but nobody will fire you. The Struggle is where self-doubt becomes self-hatred. The Struggle is when you are having a conversation with someone and you can’t hear a word that they are saying because all you can hear is the Struggle. The Struggle is when you want the pain to stop. The Struggle is unhappiness. The Struggle is when you go on vacation to feel better and you feel worse. The Struggle is when you are surrounded by people and you are all alone. The Struggle has no mercy. The Struggle is the land of broken promises and crushed dreams. The Struggle is a cold sweat. The Struggle is where your guts boil so much that you feel like you are going to spit blood. The Struggle is not failure, but it causes failure. Especially if you are weak. Always if you are weak. Most people are not strong enough. Every great entrepreneur from Steve Jobs to Mark Zuckerberg went through the Struggle and struggle they did, so you are not alone. But that does not mean that you will make it. You may not make it. That is why it is the Struggle. The Struggle is where greatness comes from.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good product managers focus the team on revenue and customers. Bad product managers focus the team on how many features competitors are building. Good product managers define good products that can be executed with a strong effort. Bad product managers define good products that can’t be executed or let engineering build whatever they want (that is, solve the hardest problem).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don’t believe in statistics. I believe in calculus.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are two kinds of cultures in this world: cultures where what you do matters and cultures where all that matters is who you are. You can be the former or you can suck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend zero time on what you could have done, and devote all of your time on what you might do. Because in the end, nobody cares; just run your company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People with the right kind of ambition would not likely use the word play to describe their effort to work as a team to build something substantial. Finally, people who use the “me” prism find it natural and obvious to speak in terms of “building out my résumé” while people who use the “team” prism find such phrases to be somewhat uncomfortable and awkward, because they clearly indicate an individual goal that is separate from the team goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Either people challenge each other to the point where they don’t like each other or they become complacent about each other’s feedback and no longer benefit from the relationship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The only thing that prepares you to run a company is running a company.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“This the real world, homie, school finished They done stole your dreams, you dunno who did it.” —KANYE WEST, “GORGEOUS”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In order to build a great technology company, you have to hire lots of incredibly smart people. It’s a total waste to have lots of big brains but not let them work on your biggest problems. &lt;strong&gt;A brain, no matter how big, cannot solve a problem it doesn’t know about.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;principle of the Bushido—the way of the warrior: keep death in mind at all times. If a warrior keeps death in mind at all times and lives as though each day might be his last, he will conduct himself properly in all his actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s no recipe for really complicated, dynamic situations. There’s no recipe for building a high-tech company; there’s no recipe for leading a group of people out of trouble; there’s no recipe for making a series of hit songs; there’s no recipe for playing NFL quarterback; there’s no recipe for running for president; and there’s no recipe for motivating teams when your business has turned to crap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note to self: It’s a good idea to ask, “What am I not doing?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“There are several different frameworks one could use to get a handle on the indeterminate vs. determinate question. The math version is calculus vs. statistics. In a determinate world, calculus dominates. You can calculate specific things precisely and deterministically. When you send a rocket to the moon, you have to calculate precisely where it is at all times. It’s not like some iterative startup where you launch the rocket and figure things out step by step. Do you make it to the moon? To Jupiter? Do you just get lost in space? There were lots of companies in the ’90s that had launch parties but no landing parties. “But the indeterminate future is somehow one in which probability and statistics are the dominant modality for making sense of the world. Bell curves and random walks define what the future is going to look like. The standard pedagogical argument is that high schools should get rid of calculus and replace it with statistics, which is really important and actually useful. There has been a powerful shift toward the idea that statistical ways of thinking are going to drive the future.”— PETER THIEL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perks are good, but they are not culture.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tip to aspiring entrepreneurs: &lt;strong&gt;If you don’t like choosing between horrible and cataclysmic, don’t become CEO.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ironically, the key to an emotional discussion is to take the emotion out of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t have world-class strengths where you need them, you won’t be a world-class company.  If you don’t know what you want, the chances that you’ll get it are extremely low.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you need to ask yourself, “If our company isn’t good enough to win, then do we need to exist at all?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Campbell: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not about the money.&amp;rdquo;
Ben Horowitz: &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s it about, Bill?&amp;rdquo;
Bill: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s about the FUCKING money.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consensus decisions about executives almost always sway the process away from strength and toward lack of weakness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Exodus executive later joked to me: “When we drove off the cliff, we left no skid marks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wartime CEO neither indulges consensus building nor tolerates disagreements. Peacetime CEO sets big, hairy, audacious goals. Wartime CEO is too busy fighting the enemy to read management books written by consultants who have never managed a fruit stand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“We walk the same path, but got on different shoes; Live in the same building, but we got different views.” —DRAKE, “RIGHT ABOVE IT”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Law of Crappy People states: For any title level in a large organization, the talent on that level will eventually converge to the crappiest person with the title.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marc: “You only ever experience two emotions: euphoria and terror. And I find that lack of sleep enhances them both.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is easy to think that the things that bother you will upset your people more. That’s not true. The opposite is true. &lt;strong&gt;Nobody takes the losses harder than the person most responsible. Nobody feels it more than you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On my grandfather’s tombstone, you will find his favorite Marx quote: “&lt;strong&gt;Life is struggle.&lt;/strong&gt;” I believe that within that quote lies the most important lesson in entrepreneurship: &lt;strong&gt;Embrace the struggle.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No matter who you are, you need two kinds of friends in your life. The first kind is one you can call when something good happens, and you need someone who will be excited for you. Not a fake excitement veiling envy, but a real excitement. You need someone who will actually be more excited for you than he would be if it had happened to him. The second kind of friend is somebody you can call when things go horribly wrong—when your life is on the line and you only have one phone call. Who is it going to be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some things are much easier to see in others than in yourself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It turns out that is exactly what product strategy is all about—figuring out the right product is the innovator’s job, not the customer’s job. The customer only knows what she thinks she wants based on her experience with the current product. The innovator can take into account everything that’s possible, but often must go against what she knows to be true. As a result, innovation requires a combination of knowledge, skill, and courage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, the judgment that you have to make is (a) is this market really much bigger (more than an order of magnitude) than has been exploited to date? and (b) are we going to be number one? If the answer to either (a) or (b) is no, then you should consider selling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Until you make the effort to get to know someone or something, you don’t know anything.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PEACETIME CEO/WARTIME CEO Peacetime CEO knows that proper protocol leads to winning. Wartime CEO violates protocol in order to win. Peacetime CEO focuses on the big picture and empowers her people to make detailed decisions. Wartime CEO cares about a speck of dust on a gnat’s ass if it interferes with the prime directive. Peacetime CEO builds scalable, high-volume recruiting machines. Wartime CEO does that, but also builds HR organizations that can execute layoffs. Peacetime CEO spends time defining the culture. Wartime CEO lets the war define the culture. Peacetime CEO always has a contingency plan. Wartime CEO knows that sometimes you gotta roll a hard six. Peacetime CEO knows what to do with a big advantage. Wartime CEO is paranoid. Peacetime CEO strives not to use profanity. Wartime CEO sometimes uses profanity purposefully. Peacetime CEO thinks of the competition as other ships in a big ocean that may never engage. Wartime CEO thinks the competition is sneaking into her house and trying to kidnap her children. Peacetime CEO aims to expand the market. Wartime CEO aims to win the market. Peacetime CEO strives to tolerate deviations from the plan when coupled with effort and creativity. Wartime CEO is completely intolerant. Peacetime CEO does not raise her voice. Wartime CEO rarely speaks in a normal tone. Peacetime CEO works to minimize conflict. Wartime CEO heightens the contradictions. Peacetime CEO strives for broad-based buy-in. Wartime CEO neither indulges consensus building nor tolerates disagreements. Peacetime CEO sets big, hairy, audacious goals. Wartime CEO is too busy fighting the enemy to read management books written by consultants who have never managed a fruit stand. Peacetime CEO trains her employees to ensure satisfaction and career development. Wartime CEO trains her employees so they don’t get their asses shot off in the battle. Peacetime CEO has rules like “We’re going to exit all businesses where we’re not number one or two.” Wartime CEO often has no businesses that are number one or two and therefore does not have the luxury of following that rule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“What would you do if capital were free?” is a dangerous question to ask an entrepreneur. It’s kind of like asking a fat person, “What would you do if ice cream had the exact same nutritional value as broccoli?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The purpose of process is communication. If there are five people in your company, you don’t need process, because you can just talk to each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Trust me.” That’s what a CEO says every day to her employees. Trust me: This will be a good company. Trust me: This will be good for your career. Trust me: This will be good for your life. A layoff breaks that trust. &lt;strong&gt;In order to rebuild trust, you have to come clean.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The difference between being mediocre and magical is often the difference between letting people take creative risk and holding them too tightly accountable. &lt;strong&gt;Accountability is important, but it’s not the only thing that’s important.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://mechowy.github.io/link/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 22:17:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mechowy.github.io/link/hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34; title=&#34;Hugo Site&#34;&gt;Hugo Main&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34; title=&#34;Hugo Themes&#34;&gt;Hugo Themes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/&#34; title=&#34;Hugo Github Source&#34;&gt;Hugo Github Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/commands/&#34; title=&#34;Hugo Command Reference&#34;&gt;Hugo Command Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discuss.gohugo.io/&#34; title=&#34;Hugo Discussion Forum&#34;&gt;Hugo Discussion Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Links for MathJax</title>
      <link>https://mechowy.github.io/link/mathjax/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 18:31:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mechowy.github.io/link/mathjax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://meta.math.stackexchange.com/questions/5020/mathjax-basic-tutorial-and-quick-reference&#34; title=&#34;StackExchange MathJax&#34;&gt;StackExchange MathJax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.martinkeefe.com/math/mathjax&#34; title=&#34;Martin Keefe&#39;s MathJax Guide&#34;&gt;Martin Keefe&amp;rsquo;s MathJax Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://doswa.com/2011/07/20/mathjax-in-markdown.html&#34; title=&#34;MathJax with Markdown&#34;&gt;MathJax with Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/index.html&#34; title=&#34;MathJax Official Documentation&#34;&gt;MathJax Official Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon</title>
      <link>https://mechowy.github.io/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 17:03:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mechowy.github.io/project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming Soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>